

Gaurav Singh

- Sin.Gaurav10@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL O SUMMARY

9+ years of experience as an Automation Test Engineer and has worked primarily in BFSI domain. Most of the experience is in Payment Solutions and Financial Banking. Searching for an opportunity where I can have growth in my skillset and become even more productive asset for the organization.

SKILLS O

- BDD Framework.
- Core java.
- Selenium WebDriver.
- JUnit and TestNG framework.
- Swift, ACH (BFSI)

- TOSCA- API/UI- Automation
- API Automation.
- Postman/SoapUI/Ready-API
- CI/CD

WORK HISTORY

SR. AUTOMATION TEST ENGINEER

02/2021 to CURRENT

MPHASIS | Pune, Maharashtra Project(s): <u>UK Lending Project.</u>

- Technology: Selenium, REST-Assured Tester;
- Business Domain: BFSI QA:
- Subject of testing: UI Automation, API Automation, Database Automation
- Testing Tools: Selenium, JAVA-8, BDD, CICD-TeamCity
- Expertise: Lead QA Automation Specialist.

SR. AUTOMATION TEST ENGINEER

05/2017 to 02/2021

Fiserv India Pvt. | Pune, Maharashtra Project(s): <u>PEP+ Direct Integrated API's</u>

- Testing and Verifying SWIFT processing.
- Checking SWIFT standards
- Testing Application Integration to third-party applications
- Verifying Messages translation for BAI files to SWIFT MT 94X and 950 messages.

Consumers expect exceptional online experiences from their financial institutions. To help meet these evolving needs'

Applications: PEP+ Direct, Positive Pay, Delete Reversal, Reverse Positive Pay, Clearing Houses (SWIFT).

Responsibilities: We have been involved in testing core functionalities of API's which were integrated with PEP+ Direct, Also verifying the integration of API with other application like Dovetail and Core PEP+ software US based and also create **NACHA** files to process the **payments** in batches.

Project(s): Prologue Financials

Prologue™ Financials from Fiserv, a fully integrated accounting solution, features enhanced, built-in automation and controls and a newly designed user interface, enabling users to increase the efficiency of financial accounting processes.

Applications: Prologue Financials, Transaction Manager. **Testing Tools:** Eclipse, TOSCA, SOAPUI and Ready API.

AARTEKONE GLOBAL SERVICES LTD.

05/2015 to 04/2017

F & I Administration. | Ahmedabad, Gujarat

LLC operates as a provider of software solutions for the administration of automotive finance and insurance products. The Company platform addresses the specific needs of every role within the lifecycle of a finance and insurance products.

Application: F&I Insurance Application.

Testing Tools: SOAPUI, Eclipse, QTP (Existing Framework), REST API.

SOFTWARE TESTER

02/2013 to 05/2015

E-Square Business Solutions | Surat, Gujarat

Worked for the project which has overall cycle how scaffold gets created and get dismantled with all the users/roles within the application, developed the application for both intranet/internet users.

Applications: Scaffolding and Management

Testing Tools: TFS, Eclipse.

TECH. SERVER OPS.

10/2011 to 11/2012

IBM, State Street Corporation Bank | Greater Noida, NCR

 Managing the outage part working as a backend technical associate, to check the Linux servers and maintain the server that doesn't caught any downtime.

EDUCATION O

Master of Computer Applications | Information Technology Sikkim Manipal University.

04/2016

GPA: 62

Bachelor of Commerce | Computer Application.

04/2012

GACC (DAVV), Indore

GPA: 65.31

CERTIFICATIONS O

Certified Tester, **ISTQB-Foundation Level and Advanced Level -Test Analyst.**Certified SCRUM **PSM I.**

Certified International Payment Systems Professional.

Certified TOSCA AS1 and AS2 Module.